Guide to the Denise Levertov Papers
Department of Special Collections
Denise Levertov papers
ca. 1945-1997
M0601
Levertov, Denise
ca. 159 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The Denise Levertov papers provide a remarkable window into the life of this important English-born, American poet. According to Kenneth Rexroth, Denise Levertov was "the most subtly skillful poet of her generation, the most profound, the most modest, the most moving." Her papers document the process of her writing, her relationships with others of her generation, and the role of this "poet in the world." The family papers (series 1), which feature substantial correspondence with Levertov's mother, with her former husband Mitchell Goodman and with her son, combine with Levertov's personal papers to offer a rich source for biographical study. The manuscripts (series 2) and notebooks (series 3) document Levertov's creative process, recording the development of individual poems from earliest drafts to printed texts. Levertov's correspondence (series 4) with other writers and public figures open numerous avenues into contemporary literary and social history. Especially important are the letters from fellow writers William Carlos Williams, Robert Creeley, Robert Duncan, Hayden Carruth, Gael Turnbull, Eve Triem, and Susan Glickman. Also important is the correspondence with Levertov's longtime editor at New Directions, James Laughlin. The remainder of the collection contains Levertov's professional papers (series 5), accumulated printed materials, and personal artifacts. Taken together, these papers provide the researcher with as complete a portrait of Levertov and her times as is currently available.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Denise Levertov, 1993
Biography / Administrative History
Denise Levertov, an Anglo-American poet who took up such social and political issues as the Vietnam war and nuclear proliferation, was born in Ilford, England, in 1923. The daughter of a prominent scholar and a Welsh mother, Levertov was privately educated in England before coming to the United States in 1948 with her husband, the American novelist Mitchell Goodman. In nearly fifty years, in 24 volumes of poems, Levertov became one of the United States's most prominent writers. Her writing is uncompromising, dignified by a spare and clear style and with an immediacy of language in the tradition of William Carlos Williams. For example, in "The ache of marriage," Levertov writes:
The ache of marriage:
thigh and tongue, beloved,
are heavy with it,
it throbs in the teeth
We look for communion
and are turned away, beloved,
each and each
It is leviathan and we
in its belly
looking for joy, some joy
not to be known outside it
two by two in the ark of
the ache of it.
Collections of her poetry include The Double Image (1946), Here and Now (1957), Overland to the Islands (1958), The Sorrow Dance (1967), Relearning the Alphabet (1970), Footprints (1972), Oblique Prayers (1984), A Door in the Hive (1989), Evening Train (1993), and Sands of the Well (1996).
Denise Levertov died on December 20, 1997. She was 74.
Chronology
1923 Oct. 24 Born Denise Levertoff, Ilford, Essex, England, second daughter of Paul Philip Levertoff and Beatrice Spooner-Jones Levertoff. Educated privately.
1940 Publishes first poem "Listening to Distant Guns" in Poetry Quarterly.-Vol. 2, no. 4 (Winter 1940), p. 96.
1946 Publishes first volume of poems, The double image (London: The Cresset Press).
1947 Serves as nurse in an English hospital at Paris. Meets Mitchell Goodman in Geneva and marries him December 2nd.
1948 Levertov and Goodman move to New York City. Kenneth Rexroth publishes six of Levertov's poems [Christmas, 1944-The Anteroom-Folding a Shirt-The Barricades-Autumn Journey-Poem ["Some are too much at home..."] in The new British poets: an anthology (Norfolk, CT: New Directions).
1949 Son Nikolai Gregor Goodman born.
1955 Denise Levertov is naturalized a United States citizen.
1957 - 1958 Lives in Mexico.
1957 First American collection, Here and now (San Francisco: City Lights Bookshop), is published.
1958 Jonathan Williams' Jargon Society publishes Overland to the islands (Highlands, NC: Jonathan Williams, Publisher), as Jargon 19.
1959 With eyes at the back of our heads (New York: New Directions).
1961 The Jacob's ladder (New York: New Directions). Becomes poetry editor for The Nation.
1962 Guggenheim Fellow.
1964 O taste and see: new poems (New York: New Directions).
1965 Writer in residence at City College of New York.
1966-1967 Teaches at Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY.
1967 The sorrow dance: poems (New York: New Directions). In praise of Krishna: songs from the Bengali. Edward C. Dimock, Jr. and Denise Levertov, trans. (Garden City: Doubleday). Out of the war shadow: an anthology of current poetry, compiled and edited by Denise Levertov. (New York: War Resisters League).
1968 A tree telling of Orpheus (Los Angeles: Black Sparrow Press). The cold spring & other poems (New York: New Directions).
1969 Embroideries (Los Angeles: Black Sparrow Press). Guillevic, Eug?ne. Selected poems. Denise Levertov, trans. (New York: New Directions). Visiting lecturer, University of California, Berkeley.
1969-1970 Visiting professor, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
1970 Relearning the alphabet (New York: New Directions). Summer poems, 1969 (Berkeley: Oyez ). A new year's garland for my students /MIT 1969-1970. (Mt. Horeb, Wis., Perishable Press). Receives honorary D.Litt. from Colby College.
1971 To stay alive (New York: New Directions).
1972 Footprints (New York: New Directions). Trip with Muriel Rukeyser to Vietnam.
1972-1978 Teaches at Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts.
1973 Conversation in Moscow (Cambridge: Hovey St. Press). The poet in the world (New York: New Directions).
1975 The freeing of the dust (New York: New Directions).
1976-1978 Poetry editor, Mother Jones.
1977 Chekhov on the West Heath (Andes, N.Y.: Woolmer/Brotherson). Modulations for solo voice (San Francisco: Five Trees Press).
1977 June 8 Beatrice Spooner-Jones Levertoff dies in Oaxaca, Mexico.
1978 Life in the forest (New York: New Directions).
1979 Collected earlier poems, 1940-1960 (New York: New Directions).
1980 Elected to American Institute of Arts and Letters.
1981 Light up the cave (New York: New Directions). Mass for the day of St. Thomas Didymus (Concord, N.H: William B. Ewert). Pig dreams: scenes from the life of Sylvia (Woodstock, Vt.: Countryman Press). Wanderer's daysong (Port Townsend, WA: Copper Canyon Press). Begins teaching at Stanford University.
1982 Candles in Babylon (New York: New Directions).
1983 Poems, 1960-1967 (New York: New Directions).
1984 Oblique prayers: new poems with 14 translations from Jean Joubert (New York: New Directions).
1987 Breathing the water (New York: New Directions). Poems, 1968-1972 (New York: New Directions).
1988 Joubert, Jean. Black iris: poems. Denise Levertov, trans. (Port Townsend, WA: Copper Canyon Press).
1989 A door in the hive (New York: New Directions).
1992 New & selected essays (New York: New Directions).
1993 Evening train (New York: New Directions).
1995 Tesserae: memories & suppositions (New York: New Directions).
1996 Sands of the well (New York: New Directions).
1997 The life around us: selected poems on nature (New York: New Directions). The stream & the sapphire: selected poems on religious themes (New York: New Directions).
1997 Feb. 1 Mitchell Goodman died of pancreatic cancer at his home in Temple, Maine. He was 73.
1997 Dec. 20 Denise Levertov died from complications from lymphoma at the Swedish Hospital in Seattle. She was 74. She is survived by her son Nikolai Gregor Goodman.
1998 New Directions releases The letters of Denise Levertov and William Carlos Williams, edited by Christopher MacGowan.
1999 A posthumous collection of Levertov's poems is released from New Directions, called This Great Unknowing: last poems.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Levertov papers are organized into twelve series.
Series 1, Family Correspondence and Papers, consists of 20 linear feet of materials, including the manuscripts of her father, the Rev. Paul Philip Levertoff, a Russian Jew who converted to Anglicism, a scholar of Jewish-Christian relations, a commentator on the Zohar, and a translator of Franz Werfel. The series also includes a vast correspondence between Levertov and her late husband Mitchell Goodman, Levertov and her mother, Beatrice Spooner-Jones Levertoff, as well as Mrs. Levertoff's extensive correspondence with her friend Margaret (Manga) Cornwell.
Series 1 is organized into six subseries: a. Family correspondence, b. Beatrice Levertoff papers, c. Paul P. Levertoff Papers, d. Mitchell Goodman Papers, e. Nikolai Goodman Papers, and f. Olga Levertoff Papers. Each of these subseries is organized with an emphasis on that person's correspondence, manuscripts, and miscellany.
Series 2, Manuscripts by Denise Levertov, houses extensive drafts of Levertov's writing. Organized by genre, including her poetry, prose, and translations, the series ranges from her earliest poems to the collection of poems she was working on at the time of her death, published posthumously by New Directions as This Great Unknowing: Last Poems (1999). The poetry is grouped by collection and organized, where possible, by individual poem. Series 2 comprises 31 boxes of materials. Denise Levertov's manuscripts are organized by genre into four subseries, which are organized chronologically: a. Poetry, b. Prose, c. Interviews, and d. Translations.
Series 3, Personal Papers, include the notebooks Levertov used throughout her adult life. These notebooks provide insight into the character of the woman and the genesis of the work. Also included are dream sketches, notes, and papers associated with Levertov's social and political activism. Series 3 comprises 16 linear feet. The personal papers contain working papers by Levertov, notes, miscellany, and the accumulata of a lifetime of activism and of reading. These papers are organized into six subseries, arranged either chronologically (as are the notebooks) or alphabetically. The subseries are: a. Notebooks, b. Biographical Papers, c. Dream Sketches, d. Notes, e. Memorabilia, and f. Social, Religious, and Political Files.
Series 4, Correspondence, is the largest series of the collection, consisting of more than 60 linear feet and 4,500 folders. Especially valuable in this series is Levertov's correspondence with her publisher James Laughlin and poets of her generation, especially William Carlos Williams, Robert Duncan, Robert Creeley, and Hayden Carruth. The correspondence is organized alphabetically by correspondent and arranged into two subseries: Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence.
Series 5, Professional Papers, contains papers associated with Levertov's professional life as a poet. The series includes business-related correspondence, documents associated with her poetry readings and her teaching career. The teaching materials include lecture notes, correspondence with students, as well as student work. This series comprises 12.5 linear feet of material. The papers are organized into four subseries: a. Correspondence, b. Awards and Honors, c. Teaching Materials, and d. Readings.
Series 6, Printed Materials, consists of printed serials, broadsides, chapbooks, articles, book reviews, and clippings, most relating to Levertov's writing or to her particular literary or personal interests. Series 6 is a useful resource for finding some rare and limited editions of Levertov's published work. Printed materials comprise approximately 19 linear feet. The series houses an extensive collection of journals, articles and other printed ephemera. Many of the publications contain pieces by or about Levertov. Together, they are helpful in starting a primary and secondary bibliography of Levertov's work. The printed materials are arranged into eight subseries: a. Serials, b. Chapbooks, c. Articles, d. Reviews, e. Broadsides, f. Clippings, g. Poems by Others, and h. Miscellany.
Series 7, Photographs and Artwork, includes photographs of Levertov and her family, including an important group of seven photos by Ralph Eugene Meatyard. It also includes drawings and sketches of Levertov, her mother Beatrice, and the juvenilia of her son Nikolai.
Series 8, Sound Recordings, includes audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes of Levertov's readings, as well as cassettes of Robert Creeley, Robert Duncan, Louis Zukofsky, Basil Bunting, and Charles Olson reading. The series has sixty cassette tapes, seven reel-to-reel tapes, and three audio discs.
Series 9, People Files, houses occasional clippings and notes pertaining to various people Levertov knew or was interested in. Series 9 consists of approximately 0.5 linear feet of material.
Series 10, Subject Files. Like series 9, the subject files house information Levertov collected on various social, religious, and political issues. Series ten consists of approximately 0.5 linear feet of material.
Series 11, Manuscripts by others, contains drafts, poems, articles, and other pieces Levertov kept, mostly sent her from friends, colleagues and students. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by author and comprise 6.5 linear feet.
Series 12, Artifacts, houses Levertov's personal memorabilia, including her father's Doctor of Divinity Degree from Lambeth.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Carruth, Hayden, 1921-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; Duncan, Robert Edward, 1919-; Fussiner, Barbara; Fussiner, Howard; Goodman, Mitchell; Goodman, Nikolai; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Levertoff, Beatrice; Levertoff, Olga; Levertoff, Paul; Levertov, Denise, 1923-; Machado, Antonio, 1875-1939; Parra, Nicanor, 1914-; Paz, Octavio, 1914-; Smith, Page; Stevens, Wallace; Triem, Eve, 1902-1992; Turnbull, Gael; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; American literature--20th century; Poets, American
Container List
- Series 1. Family Correspondence and Papers
  - a. Family Correspondence
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul P. Levertoff, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1939 Nov. - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1940 Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1940 July - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, n.d. [early 1940's?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 Jan. - Mar. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 Apr. - June (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 July - Sept. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 Oct. - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1948 Jan. - Mar. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1948 Apr. - June (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1948 July - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 Jan. - Feb. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 Mar. - May (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 June - July (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 Aug. - Sept. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 Oct - Nov. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, n.d. [late 1940's] (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 Jan. - Feb. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 Apr. - May (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 June (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 July (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 Aug. - Sept. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1950 Oct. - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1950] (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1950] (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 Jan. - Feb. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 Mar. - Apr. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 May (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 June - Aug. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 Sept. - Oct. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1951 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1951] (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1952 Jan. - Feb. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1952 Mar. - May (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1952 June - Aug. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1952 Sept. - Dec. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1952] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1953 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1953 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1953 Mar. - June (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1953 July - Sept. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1953 Oct. - Dec. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1953] (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 Jan. - Apr. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 May (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 June - July (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 Aug. - Sept. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 Oct. - Dec. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Levertov, Denise to Paul and Beatrice Levertoff, [1954] (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1954 - 1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1955 Jan. - June (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1955 July - Dec. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, n.d. [1958] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff [Christmas gift announcements], 1973 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, 1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff [fragment], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Levertov, Denise to Beatrice Levertoff [includes AMs, "At the Pond"], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, ca. 1947 - 1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, ca. 1951 - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, 1955 - 1962 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Levertov, Denise to Mitchell Goodman, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Levertov, Denise and Goodman, Mitchell to Nikolai Goodman, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, 1959 - 1960 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, 1966 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, n.d. [1979] (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, 1979 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, 1982 - 1983 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Levertov, Denise to Nikolai Goodman, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1949 - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1950 Jan. - Feb. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1950 Mar. - Apr. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1950 May - Dec. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov and Mitchell Goodman, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1954 Jan. - June (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1954 July - Dec. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1955 Jan. - June (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1959 Jan. - June (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1959 July - Dec. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1960 Jan. - June (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1960 July - Dec. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1961 Jan. - June (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Levertoff, Beatrice to Denise Levertov, 1961 July - Dec. (Box 5, Folder 22)